

■ s.martin.20@ucl.ac.uk | 🌴 sophieam.com | 🖸 sophmrtn

Research Interests

I am a PhD student on the i4Health CDT at University College London interested in applications of artificial intelligence (AI) to healthcare. My PhD focuses on the use of interpretable deep learning in medical imaging to bridge the gap between research and clinical practice. Outside of my own work, I'm also interested in and excited by physics-inspired neural networks and methods that improve robustness and generalisability.

Education

University College London London

PHD IN AI & MEDICAL IMAGING (1+3, ESPRC-FUNDED) 2020 - Present

Imperial College London

London

MSci Physics 2016 - 2020

St Angela's Ursuline School

A Level: 3A*'s (Maths, Further Maths, Physics) & 1A (History)

GCSE: 9A*s (including Maths and English Language) & 2As + FMSQ

2009 - 2014

Research Projects

Evaluating Explanation Methods in Deep Learning for Stroke Classification

University College London

MRES RESEARCH PROJECT

Oct 2020 - May 2021

• I evaluated popular explanation methods for a convolutional neural network trained to classify stroke patients from healthy controls to assess their ability to identify biologically relevant regions of interest. Supervised by Professor James Cole and Professor Frederik Barkhof.

A Network Science Perspective on Signal Propagation in the Brain

Imperial College London

MSci Research Project

Oct 2019 - May 2020

• I developed a cellular graph network to model excitation spread across structures such as small-world, stochastic model and a Barabasi-Albert hub network. This involved graph theory and criticality analysis. Supervised by Professor Kim Christensen.

Sensitivity Studies of the 5 MeV Distortion at SoLid Utilising Machine Learning

Imperial College London

BSc Research Project

Oct 2018 - May 2019

• I evaluated the use machine learning to detect a distortion in the anti-electron neutrino energy spectrum. This signal vs. background problem is highly transferable and was a useful application of statistical data analysis. Supervised by Dr Daniel Saunders.

Industry Experience ____

Illumina Cambridge

Bioinformatician, Internship

Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

- I built a pipeline that used machine learning to identify tumour-only variants from genetic data in Python.
- I used feature visualisation, engineering and hyperparameter tuning to improve performance.
- I used the Sun Grid Engine cluster computing framework to submit jobs for batch processing.

Open Energi London

DATA SCIENTIST, INTERNSHIP

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- I contributed to a project to improve asset performance for rapid grid-frequency response.
- Code was developed in Python, Git was used to collaborate with other developers and SQL was required to interact with the database.

Jaguar Land Rover London

Weight Engineer, Internship

Teaching Experience _

AI in Biomedicine & Healthcare

University College London

POSTGRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT, DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

September 2022 - Present

• This course focuses on current ML and AI trends and their application to healthcare and the need for domain-specific knowledge when processing healthcare data.

Introduction to Deep Learning

University College London

POSTGRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT, DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

• This course covers the fundamentals of deep learning, with a focus on several applications: image/test classification, segmentation and different architectures: CNNs, VAEs, RNNs and GANs. I assisted with teaching and marking and delivered a guest lecture on Model Interpretation.

Awards & Publications

AWARDS

20222nd Place, NeuroHACK Hackathon, DEMON NetworkVirtual Event2021Finalist, 15th Annual London Hopper ColloquiumVirtual Event2016Winner, Worshipful Company of Coachmakers and Coach Harness Makers' Jaguar Land Rover BursaryLondon

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Paper, Sophie A. Martin, Florence J. Townend, Frederik Barkhof, James H. Cole, *Interpretable deep learning for dementia: a systematic review.*

In-Preparation

Conference Paper, Liam F. Chalcroft, Jiongqi Qu, Sophie A. Martin, Iani JMB Gayo, Giulio V. Minore, Imraj

RD Singh, Shaheer U. Saeed, Qianye Yang, Zachary M. C. Baum, Andre Altmann, Yipeng Hu, Development and evaluation of intraoperative ultrasound segmentation with negative image frames and multiple observer labels. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-87583-1_3

ASMUS

Academic Activities

2022 Reviewer, Neurolmage

Journa

Other Activities

The Blackett Lab Family C.I.C

London

DIRECTOR OF MEDIA & MARKETING

Jun 2020 - Present

• I create social media content, marketing materials and lead website development and maintenance.

Project Partners Education CIO

London

BOARD TRUSTEE

Mar 2020 - Present

• I help to facilitate the growth of the charity by consulting on teaching materials and content.

Google GetAhead Program

Virtual Event

PARTICIPANT

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

• I participated in a 6-week virtual program for selected CS students across EMEA. The program involved technical challenges, YouTube live trainings and interview workshops.

Skills

Programming Python, TensorFlow, Pytorch, MatLab, Bash, SGE Computing, SQL, Git, LaTeX

Web HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Javascript

General UK Driving License, English (Native), French (B1)